Over 450 years,
East Timor was colonized by Portugal.
9 days after its liberation in 1975,
however, lndonesia invaded
this island nation and 60,000 were killed.
ln the next 24 years during the occupation,
200,000, a quarter of the population died.
ln 1999, lndonesia withdrew
under the pressure from the
international community.
However, as the pro lndonesian militia rioted
against their independence...
thousands of people were killed
and more lost their homes as a result.
ln 2002, East Timor finally became independent
but hatred and conflicts still remain.
This film was inspired by amazing true events
about a Korean soccer coach
...and his young players from East Timor.
2003, Sumatra, lndonesia
This is crazy!
Now Indonesia rainy season.
Many, many rains.
Korean rain, nothing compared to here.
The JungIe is a dangerous pIace.
A snake bite. You die here.
And a crocodiIe bite you. You die too.
Hey, we got a gun. Why scared?
Whatever you say,
those crocodiIes are mine.
So go ahead! Go! Go!
Rain. It wiII rain any minute.
This is the shortcut to the heaven
if you continue.
To make money, you gotta go
where no one eIse dares.
Go ahead.
Let's hunt some crocodiIes.
Go! Go!
That son of a bitch runs out on me?
C'mon. C'mon.
What I Iost from Iumber business,
Executive Producer RYU Jeong-hun
I'II make it up from hunting crocodiIes.
I wiII.
Co-Producer PARK Un-kyoung
The noodIe's ready.
Producers KlM Tae-kyun RYU Jeong-hun
Producer KlM Jun-jong
Damn, it's hot!
Screenplay by KlM Gwang-hoon
Directed by KlM Tae-kyun
Medan Hospital in lndonesia
I'm serious, sis.
I got a burn and MaIaria.
I'm not kidding.
The creditors are after my ass.
I gotta get outta here.
PARK Hee-soon
Who? Shin?
That's Woo-suk's matter.
GO Chang-seok
What?
SHlMlZU Kei
How can you caII your onIy
Brother a con man?
HeIIo? Don't hang up. Hey!
It didn't go through.
I'm done.
Director of Photography CHUNG Han-chul
Lighting by PARK Gun-woo
Production Designer KlM Hyun-ok
Recording by JEON Sang-jun
Stay away!
Mr. Kim Won-kwang!
Hi
Do you know me?
That was 1983...
Junior Cup in Qatar, right?
The Korean team was eIiminated
in the first round.
But that team was fuII of taIent.
Were you in soccer?
No, I remember you when you were
with the Hyundai Motors team.
Of course, you wouIdn't know me.
I'm YOO from Yonhap News Agency.
WeII, I'm Kim Won-kwang.
I said I know who you are.
You're kind of famous.
- I wasn't even that great as soccer?
- Every Korean in Indonesia knows about you
who bareIy survived in the Sumatra jungIe.
Don't you have anything better to cover?
So the damn money...
I wanted to make money so I quit pIaying.
I tried everything but nothing worked.
I quit soccer
but I was a baII pIayer aII my Iife.
How was I going to make money?
With what?
So what are you going to do now?
Wait, wait. I'm not done yet.
So I borrowed money to start...
Yes, you borrowed money
and started a factory in Indonesia.
But you got cheated and went bankrupt.
How do you know?
- You just toId me minutes ago.
- ReaIIy?
But what about now?
WeII, what shouId I do?
What are they doing here?
Mr. KIM, have you heard of East Timor?
East what?
The 1st independent state
of the 21st century.
Since they got nothing, it's a start.
Dili, East Timor
Or should l say, since it's a start,
they got nothing?
But l think that place has one thing for sure.
Hope.
Hope. Yeah right.
Mister, which car?
No thank you.
Which car? Mister?
I don't have a car.
Get Iost!
I appreciate it but...
You didn't have to push him that hard.
That's too much.
Hey, are you okay?
Hey! Mr. Kim!
You...
Me, James!
You James?
Show it to me.
You Iook...
Yes! Me, James! Yes!
Different... Nice to meet you.
WeIcome to East Timor!
Get in the car!
Hey, hey, hey!
Get away from my car!
Mister, one doIIar...
One doIIar, Mister.
Get the fuck off!
Mister. One doIIar!
One doIIar.
Mister, one doIIar.
Give me a doIIar. Damn it.
Ramos
UN gives money soon.
Once they get the money,
there's so much to do.
We gotta buiId houses. New roads.
We gotta buiId factories.
God, there's gonna be so much happening.
I'm so gIad to be working with a feIIow Korean.
Drink it.
The quaIity of coffee here is exceIIent.
We're going to be rich soon.
Rich soon?
Very very rich!
You reaIIy do have a vision.
Me?
Yes!
So, the coffee mountain is... nearby?
No, no, no....
Oh, you just rest today.
Tomorrow, your Iife wiII change forever.
The smeII of money.
SmeII the money.
Hey! James!
Oh god!
Long time.
How are you doing, Mr. PARK?
UN is after your ass.
Get Iost, you sIimy weaseI.
You want me to make a caII?
James. Who?
Why are you hitting my head?
See you!
See you my ass.
James!
Did he taIk about coffee again?
That son of a bitch never changes
his repertoire.
Sorry. I'm Park from the Korean Embassy.
You arrived today, right?
Coffee or construction,
there's nothing for you here.
There are two types of Koreans
who come here.
Either you get conned
by someone like James or you con others.
Please just go back.
There's absolutely nothing.
You gotta be kidding me.
Good morning! Did you check out aIready?
Let me give you a ride.
No thanks. There are pIenty of cabs.
C'mon. PIease accept
a feIIow Korean's offer.
I'm aIright.
PIease. Let me take you to the airport.
You're afraid I may not Ieave?
No, that's not it. It's stiII dangerous here.
Sometimes, there are gunfights
and expIosions once in a whiIe.
Isn't it my job to protect our citizens
in such a dangerous pIace?
Sorry.
Tua
Where are you going?
Not bad.
Stupid!
You good for nothing.
I'm gonna kiII you.
Ramos, you're dead meat.
What are you doing here?
Let's go.
I'm not Ieaving here.
It won't work, $60?
Are you crazy?
This wouId cost 6 bucks back home.
Hey, this is Nike.
And it's a knock-off.
A knock-off?
It's got the Iogo and everything.
I'm sure it's not that hard to fake them.
You see the kids here
pIaying soccer aII the time?
BaIIs and shoes wiII eventuaIIy wear off.
This is a sure thing for business,
I'm teIIing you.
Wonder why there's no sports store
in East Timor?
So that's why we caII it monopoIy.
Got it?
Put it over there.
Mr. ambassador, Iet's take a picture.
I want to put it up here.
Let's see.
Yes, you can stand there.
PARK, you stand there.
Marjo, take it.
Make sure the store sign is in the frame.
WeIcome to the store.
WeIcome..
These are soccer shoes.
$60.00
SpeciaI discount, $35.
See you again.
See you what?
That famiIy shouId do wrestIing,
not soccer.
One pair in 2 months, man!
Name, phone number and address.
LastIy you write down your signature here.
It wouId be 300 doIIars a month.
If you're Iate 3 months,
we take the car back.
MonthIy...he's good.
Here's your key.
He knows how to run business.
Not Iike someone...
Like who?
Get away.
Drive safeIy!
Everyone seems to want jeeps.
Oh, it Iooks deIicious.
Thank you.
Mr. PARK guarantees
so I Iend you money.
Me? Guarantee?
I don't do that to peopIe
with no monthIy income.
It's so deIicious
Fish casseroIe is the best.
Everyone Iook over here.
Attention pIease.
You got them aII?
This is how you pay.
Motavio
Why are you Iate?
I'm taIking. Later.
In your Ianguage,
the ziziIan system.
It's a credit instaIIment to be precise.
How do you say it in EngIish?
Trust, something Iike that.
Anyway, it means I trust you.
I give them to you.
And what do you do?
Take them.
And this is...
hey, pay attention.
It's important.
And you donate $1 a day to me.
What did I say?
You give one doIIar to me everyday.
Just Iike that.
Two months and done. OK?
Might be more expensive
than if you just buy them.
But you can't afford,
so it's a good choice, right?
Listen and repeat.
Good choice.
Good choice!
I say Good,
you say Choice.
Good.
Choice.
Good!
Put them on.
Jon, you can't even stop him?
Good job!
With the cIeats on,
you now pIay good.
Nice. Very good.
WeII, today is the first day
you pay me a doIIar, remember?
One doIIar.
Riki...and next Ata,
You atta bo!
Ricardo, Abebi, Good!
Next. Abai.
And you pay, Siku.
Okay, who's next?
Dinu.
Why is he staring at me Iike that?
Who's next? Motavio.
Hey, you.
Come over here.
What's your name?
Tua
Tua!
You want them?
One doIIar!
Next, Motavio!
Yes, pass it through. Shoot!
What are you doing?
You gotta make the through pass
right away.
What are you doing?
Shoot! You might as weII hand it
over to the goaIie.
And you miss it?
Is this some comedy cIub?
Marjo!
Stop watering and catch the fIies.
I'm not Marjo.
I am Major.
Big difference.
Make the through pass quickIy.
Shoot! Right!
Good! Good!
You gotta do the pass pIay.
Pass pIay.
Good. Hey, don't dribbIe.
Pass, center the baII.
Right, that's how you pIay.
Nice. Nice.
And what's that?
What the heII is that?
On a sacred fieId.
You Korean, Ieave!
What? Who is this punk teIIing me
what to do?
You, why bother the kids?
Bother?
Yes.
Don't take the money from the kids.
Ah, you must've thought...
The money isn't for the fieId.
It's for the cIeats.
It's a misunderstanding.
For the cIeats?
Yeah, you moron.
Don't come back here again.
Do you understand?
An annoying bastard Iike him.
They are everywhere.
Why do they have to be in my way?
It's another hot day.
Looks deIicious.
Mr. KIM, I heard you made a big hit
by Ieasing soccer shoes to chiIdren.
My interest.
Where's my monthIy interest?
Good saIes but no income?
But I'm okay
because Mr. PARK guaranteed.
Oh, Mr. KIM,
doing a sports business in DiIi...
I don't think it's a good idea.
Because you gotta have money.
Even with soccer and basebaII.
You need money to pIay sports.
Here, everybody poor.
They have to work.
But the kids here just pIay baII.
And no work.
No money, no soccer and no future.
Fish-Iooking sIimebaII.
Who says you can't pIay baII
if you're poor?
He says he'II pay the interest
on time every month.
By the way, no casseroIe?
It's aImost ready.
One doIIar! One doIIar!
You're Siku, right?
You never skipped. Great.
You gotta be Iike him.
Dinu, you aIso paid on time.
You kids are bad.
How can you skip on payments?
Ata. Attaboy!
What's this?
You can't just return the worn shoes.
I can't beIieve you guys.
Mr. KIM!
I raised it.
It's bigger than other roosters.
Lots of meat.
PIease, don't take away my shoes.
Oh, man. Put them down.
Put down the shoes.
It's aIright.
If not today,
tomorrow. Or the next day.
If not,
whenever you've got the money.
It's aIright.
Whenever you have it.
POONG, this is an investment.
Investment.
KIM, what are you doing over there?
This is reaIIy the Iast time.
It's not Iooking good here, either.
Not good.
I got it.
Hey, I can't hear you.
HeIIo? HeIIo?
Never mind.
Take care.
HeIIo, is it SangchuI?
I started a new business
and it Iooks promising.
FinaI term?
Oh, you shouId go back to study.
I'II hang up.
Sorry to distract you.
And pIease teII mom I caIIed...
Even with the shoes,
we can't pIay on the fieId.
And one doIIar a day is too much for me.
Hey, you!
Hey! Mr. Kim. WeIcome, weIcome.
You wanna buy this?
15 doIIars for seven fish.
Okay. Mr. Kim?
Okay I'm not.
My kids are happy
with their new shoes
and why are you bothering them?
Bothering?
I never bothered them.
I just tried to stop you
from tricking them.
Trick them?
How?
PIaying soccer barefoot is
..dangerous.
You gotta be weII equipped
in sports.
And the technique..gets better...
Upgraded.
So this isn't your scam to seII soccer shoes
but you're here to improve them?
That's right.
You're pretty smart.
Prove it to me.
Prove?
Show me the proof you mean that.
OK. Then, Iet's pIay a match.
What?
Your team and my team,
Iet's have a match.
If you win, I'II Ieave the fieId.
But...
If we win,
mind your own business.
Okay, okay. Mr. Kim.
When do you wanna do it?
10 days...
I need some time.
10 days Iater.
Okay. But Iet's aIso bet a pig.
OK. Bet as many as...
one pig is good.
You're reaIIy doing it?
I don't know. I reaIIy don't.
Don't ask me any more.
So you act first and think Iater.
It was nonsense from the moment you decided
to seII cIeats in this poor country.
This wasn't gonna work.
Why didn't you say so before?
I did teII you every time
I saw you.
Shut up!
How much is a pig here?
A pig? I guess $300?
What?
Why is it so expensive?
There are pigs everywhere
on the street.
What costs them so much?
Fetch me two baIIs.
You're in. Next.
Wow!
No. Next.
He's good. Why not?
Too short.
Are you recruiting a basketbaII team now?
Next.
You're a boy or a girI?
Boys onIy.
Next. Next.
From now on,
you're on my team.
You are my team.
I'm your coach. You're my pIayers.
Understood?
Yes, sir.
You do as you're toId.
If not, no uniform.
And no cIeats. OK?
OK.
Good.
You can't get soccer fieId back
with this!
Soccer fieId.
Think of a grass fieId.
You wanna pIay in the mud forever?
It Iooks hard.
GIad you're not doing it, right?
Let's take a break.
Get some water.
How come we just run aII day
and don't pIay footbaII?
I quit. What about you?
I dunno. I'm just tired.
Losers.
Weren't you aII over him
Iike beggars for the free shoes?
What?
Forget it. I don't wanna argue
with a bum Iike you. Antonio?
The Day of the Pig-staked Match
Hey, what the heII is this?
This is my team.
They're not kids. They're aII aduIts,
you bastard.
Why? Something wrong there?
It's my team.
That's not what we agreed on.
It's a match between
your team and mine. Remember?
Why, you scared?
How dare you whisper into my ear?
You sIimy bastard.
Listen.
Riki, you just run.
Look around and pass it to him.
Long pass. Okay?
Yo! Don't get scared.
You crying? Scared?
Are you out of your mind?
C'mon. Let's go!!!
It's okay, it's okay. Let's go!
You gotta bIock him. BIock him.
He's reaIIy good. He couId pIay
in the Indonesian pro Ieague.
They have pro teams in Indonesia?
You didn't know?
It's these kids' dream.
It's their ticket out
if they couId make it to Indonesia.
Park, can you Iend me $200
and buy me a pig?
Bon appetite!
Mr. Kim, I heard you foIded your business.
Is that true?
You toId him aIready?
No, I work.
Work?
I have 2 jobs
untiI I get the pig back.
Two jobs?
You got 2 jobs, too.
SeII cars and Ioan money.
You're doing it again?
Last time was a warm up.
If I train them hard,
no one can beat us, even an aduIt team.
Soccer isn't about strength.
It's about technique pIus teamwork
Anyhow I won't give up
untiI I get my pig back.
Ah, you're making me feeI bad.
Soccer isn't about being good
with the baII.
You gotta be big and taII.
You're short and smaII.
Hey, you!
You shouId pass right away.
Concentrate!
It's not Iike a nationaI team.
Why don't you Iet him pIay?
When you're IittIe, it won't matter.
But when he gets oIder
and he isn't big or good enough.
That becomes miserabIe.
Now you're worried
about their future.
Why don't you worry about the pig first?
Don't ignore my brother!
You stupid Korean.
Excuse me.
How do I find this pIace?
Go straight that way.
Thank you.
Ramos!
Anybody home?
Ramos, Hi!
Don't you wanna pIay with us?
Go. I ain't pIaying with you.
Hey, Iet me finish it.
Korean!
What are you doing here?
I... I'm just... CaIm down, pIease.
What's going on?
He was spying on us.
What are you doing here?
I'm not here for you.
I have business with your brother.
He's so taIented that
I want to train him properIy.
You train Ramos?
Yes.
You?
You train Ramos?
Stop dreaming!
I train him. Not you.
Next year,
I wiII take him to Indonesia.
Pro? Do you know anything
about professionaI footbaII?
You know nothing.
Just stay out of it.
If you join us, I'II get you nice cIeats.
Of course, it's free
Your brother may be a good pIayer
but he's not buying you shoes.
I offer them to you to recruit you.
I'm recruiting your brother.
This is the worId of pro.
The pro worId is...
crueI.
Hey! Korean.
I'm warning you.
You just wanna seII the soccer shoes to the kids.
Remember?
Man, you keep annoying...
Ramos, it's up to you.
Tensions between east and west escalate.
Grace period to register the assault weapons.
This is getting intense.
It couId get worse.
Many are hurrying home.
We have Iess than 10 Koreans Ieft.
This couId turn into a big riot.
What's there to fight
about in this smaII Iand?
You got pepper sauce?
Pepper sauce!
He's too good to be wasted.
What? Where is it?
What?
Pepper sauce.
It's somewhere.
This is for your dinner.
If I join you,
can I reaIIy go to an Indonesian team?
If you're good.
Promise me.
How can I promise such thing?
Ramos!
Good! Ramos!
You're doing good.
Do it right! Look at Ramos.
One more match for a pig.
Again?
You want to Iose the game Mr. KIM?
This game three pigs!
We have strong appetites.
Fine. Pick the time and day.
We'II be there.
You shouId practice
if you don't want your ass kicked.
What's so funny about?
C'mon, take it from me!
Are you OK? Motavio! Motavio!
The wound is minor
but I'm worries about his eyes.
His eyes?
He damaged his eyesight
because of maInutrition.
Happens a Iot here.
If you don't do anything about it,
he may go bIind.
BIind?
Write them down, POONG.
Cyan Soft CapsuIe,
Coenzyme Q10.
These are eye nutrients.
Try to send them ASAP.
And some vitamins.
Okay? Thanks, bro.
KIM!
I toId you
something might happen.
Hey, what are they?
Watch out!
Korean dipIomats.
We're Korean dipIomats.
Do they actuaIIy fire guns?
You think they're carrying toy guns?
What about my kids?
Who cares about the kids now?
Bro, Iet me come with you.
No, you stay here.
Don't you come outside.
I'm coming with you.
PIease Iet me come.
Bro!
Don't you come outside.
Bro, Iet me come with you.
Let's just wait here for a whiIe.
One faIse move
and we're in big troubIe.
Hey, that's my Ramos.
Ramos!
What are you taIking about?
Why wouId he be here?
Ramos!
KIM!
Gosh, KIM!
Ramos!
Hey, Ramos!
This way!
Help me!
What's wrong?
What are you doing?
He's Korean.
What the heII are you saying?
I think a Korean got shot.
I wouId know every Korean here.
I heard him.
He screamed in Korean!
This is insane.
Open it. Hurry up!
Someone's dying.
PIease heIp me.
Oh, Mr. SHIN!
You know him?
He arrived yesterday.
HeIp me.
I don't wanna die.
Ah, my head!
Let go if you want me to heIp you.
Hey, Major!
You didn't go home?
Boss, I guarded our shop.
Hey!
Tua!
You Iike it?
DeIicious.
Where do you Iive?
In a church.
Church?
You have no home?
What about your parents?
They died during the war.
ReaIIy?
My brother runs weII. He's fast.
How much is it?
5 doIIars.
Are you kidding?
It's expensive.
Are you sure this is it?
Is this Motavio's pIace?
Who is it?
Motavio, you scared the heII out of me.
Where have you been?
Soccer...
What about it?
Aren't we pIaying any more?
There are no kids.
Anyhow...
How's your eyes?
Pig, we have to get it back.
And the fieId, too.
Mr. KIM, Iet's go pIay.
You rascaIs.
Hey, Ramos!
Where's your brother?
Korean, what's up?
One more match for 3 pigs.
Anytime.
2 o'cIock. Next week.
You're Iaughing?
Don't forget.
Ramos!
You're coming, right?
You're a pro.
Motavio, pass!
Center the baII. Motavio, run!
You were Iate. Again.
Riki, center it.
Good. Once more.
Idiot. You can't even do it.
Ramos,
you go run 10 Iaps around the beach.
Motavio, back in your position.
Bring the baII. Bring it to me!
You want me to do it?
Go!
Tua.
You want to pIay with your friends?
You reaIIy want to?
Okay. I'II Iet you pIay.
But since you're shorter than others,
you have to work twice as hard. Okay?
Josephine..
Are you crying
in front of your sister?
Riki! Centering number 2.
You get to it Iate.
Motavio, you gotta run faster.
Riki, imagine Ramos' position
in your head. Okay?
Okay!
WeII, good.
Good! Again!
The Day of the Rematch
Mr. KIM, we brought the pigs.
We'II give you discounts. Buy them.
You Iousy sons of bitches.
Go away, my team wiII win.
Go to the other side.
Ramos!
KIM,
what have you done to the kids?
Wow!
We're gonna win! We wiII!
Hey, you Iosers!
Right! Just Iike that!
Focus! Stupid!
It's so compIicated!
I heard Ramos' brother got hurt
by Motavio's famiIy.
During the civiI war,
Ramos' uncIe kiIIed Motavio's father.
The probIem just doesn't end there.
The kids wiII remember everything.
And they wiII seek revenge.
They bareIy got independent
from PortugaI and Indonesia.
They don't know who's the enemy
and who's the friend.
Thinking I'd make money
in this forsaken pIace,
where peopIe are stiII shooting
at each other.
How pitifuI I am!
Mr. KIM, how about a match
with the Indonesian Kids
in West Timor?
If you find a common enemy
outside here,
I'm sure they wiII stop fighting each other
and stick together.
An internationaI tournament?
In where?
Hiroshima. What do you think?
Isn't it a great idea?
Keep dreaming.
Dream!
Yes, that's what they need.
They need to dream.
Dreams shouId be reaIistic.
In such a poverty-stricken country.
Soccer shouId be just a pastime.
Hey, who says you can't dream big
if you're poor?
I thought better of you.
No, I meant...
how are you get them to Hiroshima?
See, that's why I came here to see you.
Me? Why?
Why? Why did I come see you?
The question is why.
Hey, you're tense here.
This isn't a soccer association.
This is an embassy.
I ain't the Minister of Sports.
Right, the Minister of Sports.
You couId meet him.
A great idea.
Shut up! You think it's some joke?
Get out of my way.
The minister isn't someone
you caII up and visit.
Hey, I'm going.
ReaIIy going there.
Then, are we fIying there?
You wanna swim to Japan? SiIIy.
Now, you gotta work harder.
Don't fight each other.
You'II embarrass yourseIves
in front of the worId, got it?
Okay.
We are one team.
Team Timor-Leste.
Okay.
If you do weII there,
you couId get recruited.
Understood?
Understood!
Are you out of your mind?
You shouId say, yes sir.
I taught you that, didn't I?
Anyhow..
Understood?
Yes, sir.
It's aII EngIish.
Park, you shouId fiII it in for me.
It's impossibIe for me.
Don't waste your time.
I toId you it's not gonna happen.
I have an idea.
You shouId just heIp me
with the EngIish stuff.
Do you speII your first name "Ki" or "Gi?"
I'II pick "Gi."
You're a maIe, right?
What's this?
Coach PARK In-gi.
Have you Iost your mind?
Do I Iook Iike I'm on vacation?
I'm a dipIomat
from the RepubIic of Korea.
They said we needed 2 coaches.
Why don't you take a break?
You work too hard.
No wonder you Iook oIder.
I can't do that..
I need to go to Korea...
to have a bIind date.
How are you feeIing?
I'm aIright. Thanks.
I brought the man you wanted to meet.
Mr. KIM Won-kwang.
KIM Won-kwang?
You're KIM Won-kwang?
How couId he do this to me?
I saved his Iife.
Didn't you borrow money from everyone
in Indonesia for your Iumber business?
Mr. SHIN is one of them.
No, it wasn't me. I don't know him.
You know it. You saw it.
So you have to go back
to SeouI and expIain.
Your being here isn't resoIving this.
Of course, our embassy won't
or has any authority to send you back, Mr. KIM.
But because you're invoIved
with the chiIdren here,
this couId be a sensitive matter.
FrankIy, it is in our best interest
to recommend you return to Korea.
Stupid bureaucrats.
They're the same everywhere.
Mr. Ambassador was being considerate.
Considerate?
You mean by asking me to disappear...
I got scammed, too.
If I knew how to swindIe,
why am I stiII broke?
I think you shouId return home quietIy
instead of getting kicked out
because of the rumor.
I thought I was finaIIy off to a good start.
When I get oIder, I'II kiII you.
No, I'II kiII you
before you have a chance.
Hey, you bastards,
what are you doing now?
Sure, you don't deserve to pIay soccer.
I kidded myseIf.
Go back home.
Go fight or shoot at each other.
I don't care. Go back to your Iife.
Poong, remember that time...
when we were pIaying baII
behind the Oscar Theatre?
Of course, I remember it.
If you think about it,
it was the best time of my Iife.
We were just happy to pIay baII.
Hey, just come back
if you're done there.
l have a school coaching gig for you.
The pay is good.
What eIse are we good at?
Think it over.
A chance like this doesn't come often.
Hey, are you listening?
Hey, did you faII asIeep?
I'm a fooI, right?
You're not exactIy...
Okay, it's aII my fauIt.
Don't mind what I said
in front of the Ambassador.
Just make sure
you don't screw up again.
Do you know what my nickname was
when I was pIaying back then?
Miss BaII because I missed the baII
whenever I had a chance for a goaI.
You're not making any sense.
Let's go get some drinks.
I think...
I'm gonna back to Korea.
Do you reaIIy beIieve
he's gonna make you a pro?
I'm just getting ready
for the tournament.
PeopIe found out he was a crook
and now he is running back
to his country.
It was just an act to seII soccer shoes.
Ramos, I toId you.
We got each other.
Don't trust the foreigners.
Let's eat.
Ramos! Ramos! Ramos!
Ramos!
Be weII.
Just give away
the rest to the kids.
Thanks for everything, Major.
You're not going to see them?
It wouIdn't be easy if I saw them.
You weren't gonna Ieave
when I asked you.
Let's not taIk about it, okay?
Let me know
when you're in SeouI.
Take care.
Mr. KIM, Ramos is
at the poIice station.
What?
Ramos!
How couId they handcuff a kid?
It's just a car stereo.
PIease step aside.
Wait! Wait a minute.
He had his car decked up
with expensive stuff.
How much is that stuff?
It isn't just a car stereo.
It's Bang and OIufsen.
So how much is it?
4 grand and he wrecked it
as he was steaIing it.
What the heII did you do that for?
Hey, don't do it.
Stay out of it.
Are you a thief?
I said, don't do it.
Mind your own business.
Why did you steaI?
For what?
I wanted to go to
Indonesia for a tryout.
We can't go to Hiroshima any more.
I can't show the worId how good I am.
PIease forgive him.
I wiII work for you
untiI I can pay you back.
PIease forgive him.
PIease.
With those Iimping Iegs?
PIease take this. It's aII I have.
He's onIy 11 years oId.
And forgive him.
Forgive him. PIease.
Mind your own business.
Don't you dare show
your faIse pride, son.
Ramos!
I'm sorry...
for faiIing your trust.
Mr. KIM, pIease don't go.
Mr. KIM, I'II work harder.
Mr. KIM, pIease stay with us.
Mr. KIM, pIease don't go.
Don't Ieave us.
Stay with us.
Man, I was so ashamed...
I couIdn't Iook the kids in the eye.
They're good kids.
I wonder what they see in you.
I guess so.
By the way, you'II pass it up?
I heard about the coaching job in SeouI.
I'm onIy interested..
in coaching nationaI teams.
The truth is...
It wasn't Iike I was scamming peopIe.
If I were that kind of a person,
wouId I risk my Iife to save a stranger?
Huh, who asked you to save me?
You were bIeeding and desperate
for your Iife back then.
You grabbed my head so hard
and my hair feII off...
No wonder they caII you a fraud
since you're so meddIing.
And on top of that...
you're trying go to Hiroshima?
How did you know?
Did you hire a private eye or something?
I pIaced a caII to the Ambassador.
Go visit him.
Excuse me?
What for?
Aren't you going to meet
the Minister of Sports?
Thank you, OsvaIdo.
I'II be in touch.
At Ieast we got the bIessing
from the Minister.
What good is that if you have a passport
but no money?
Where's your spirit?
You siIIy boy.
Who poses Iike
that for a passport?
Stupid.
Wilson
Tua
Motavio
Alexon
Antonio
Abai
Marito
Jon
Nelson
Ricardo
Ata
Ramos
Yes, 17 peopIe.
From DiIi to Hiroshima.
Money? No.
No, not a probIem.
Okay. Thanks.
Excuse me, Mr. Vic?
Nice to meet you. I'm Kim.
Here's the document for the kids
here for the Hiroshima...
Soccer... Match... No airfare.
Their dreams...
Man, I'm going crazy.
Let's see how it goes.
Tua.
Why did you bring it here?
Ramos, you can do this.
Thank you.
Mr. KIM, I'm not sure
if you can get the airfare this way.
I'm just trying.
I just do my best.
How about the broadcast rights?
Broadcast?
You're joking?
These are eye nutrients.
And these are vitamins.
Do not Iose them.
That's not how you attract customers.
Gotta speak up.
Thirty fish for two doIIars.
Two doIIars.
If we don't pay by tomorrow,
the reservation is canceIIed.
You wouId have your ass kicked anyway.
There's next time.
It's raining.
Get in.
It's raining!
It's raining.
C'mon.
PARK!
Do you know why I'm trying so hard to go there
when we have no chance of winning?
Yes, why?
I just wanted to finish something.
Finish what?
I wouId aIways start something
but never finish them. Never.
I thought I couId get
to the finish Iine with the kids...
where I've never been aIone.
Maybe...
I'm not meant to be.
The story of my Iife.
I don't know how to do this but...
In East Timor,
the first independent state of the 21st Century...
What am I doing?
It's too hard.
No, no.
Not everyone can write...
In East Timor,
the first independent state of the 21st Century...
It's youth soccer team Ied
by a Korean coach...
they haven't been abIe to come
with the airfare
and it's been a huge Ietdown for the kids...
SangchuI, can you hear me weII?
Why suIking?
You did terribIe at the exam. So what?
You can do better next time.
If not, there's aIways the next one.
And the one after that
and another one.
You know the story of Don Quixote?
Yes, you charge Iike Don Quixote!
Son, do you know how to say "cheer up" here?
It's Porsa.
SangchuI, you're the man.
Porsa, my son!
He's stiII there, huh?
KIM! KIM!
Has he gone mad or something?
It's aII good.
We're going, we can go!
Look at this.
After Mr. KlM Won-kwang's story
came out,
Basic House
decided to sponsor the air travel
of the entire East Timor
youth soccer team
for their participation
in the Hiroshima Rivelino Cup.
The local clothing co. has been sponsoring
youth soccer for many years...
We did it!
Hey, are you about to cry?
You're gonna cry.
Why cry?
We're going.
We're going to Japan.
Hiroshima, 2004
Let's cheer more.
It's onIy 2 goaIs.
Okay?
Cheer up.
I don't expect us to win
but scoring a goaI wouId be nice.
It's freezing.
Mr. Dojo.
Are the kids okay
in this weather?
They're aIright.
ReaIIy?
Mr. Dojo, thank you.
Oh, sorry.
HeIIo, yes, yes.
Mr. David PIease.
HeIIo Mr. Dojo.
Yes, yes.
We're good to go.
Now connecting with Hiroshima.
Assist him!
Riki, center the baII.
The other side.
Is he okay?
Let's not wait for the second haIf.
Let's repIace him with Ramos.
Motavio?
How's your eyes?
Josephine, it's ready.
Riki, Ricardo, Ata,
Siku, Dinu, Pendi.
Tua.
Ramos.
That's it.
Motavio!
You did good.
Boys, you don't have to win.
Just do your best with no regret.
We're not done yet, right?
C'mon, guys.
Chin up!
AIright, Iet's go!
PIease.
I want to pIay.
Let me pIay.
I won't Iet you down.
Now, we're connecting
with Hiroshima.
The second haIf is about to start.
Japan is Ieading 2:0.
Our pIayers must be inexperienced...
and not adjusted to the coId weather.
But we expect our pIayers to pIay weII
in the second haIf.
Motavio!
Can you make it work?
You can't change the pIayers
on the fIy Iike that.
We came aII the way here.
Let him pIay as much as he wants.
Look at the scoreboard.
You've given up aIready.
Who asked you to come aIong?
Guess who picked me as a coach.
Ramos dribbIes.
Ramos charges
on the Ieft sideIine.
Motavio is near the penaIty area.
Ramos!
Pass it to Motavio.
Ramos faiIs to pass
and dribbIes forward again.
Ah, that was a perfect centering opportunity,
but they just missed it.
Let's go with the pIan.
Motavio, first haIf.
Ramos, second haIf.
If they get in to a fight,
it'II be an internationaI disgrace.
See. Look at them.
Take one of them out.
Mr. Dojo who's at the game teIIs us...
our pIayers are very good.
But they must be not ready
for the internationaI competition.
Ramos now possesses the baII again.
He's charging very fast.
Ramos just got knocked down
with a vicious tackIe from Japan.
Great! Nice there!
Motavio's getting deep
into the goal line!
Great pass could lead into a goal!
GOAL!
It's the first goaI ever
for an East Timor team
on an internationaI stage.
I'm proud of the young pIayers!
President, Xanana Gusmao
Tua tosses it over to Ramos.
Motavio charges in, too.
One-two pass between him
and Ramos.
Now you're confident
we can win the damn thing?
Winning's good.
But even if we Iose,
there's aIways the next time.
I'm just gIad this isn't the end.
Remember I said before,
I couId get to the finish Iine
with the kids?
You said you weren't sure about it.
I am now.
Because they trust me.
That's aII I need.
Now it's a tie game.
The peopIe of Timor-Leste,
you shouId be proud of our pIayers.
One more goaI and the victory is ours.
Tua is charging again rapidIy.
Toward the penaIty area.
FouI!
That's a fouI inside the penaIty area.
It's a penaIty kick
for Team East Timor.
There's one minute Ieft.
You can do it! Come on Ramos!
He Iost it! He Iost it!
The injury time is aImost over.
This is the Iast chance.
The Iast corner kick of the game.
There's not much time Ieft.
Time's aImost up.
Shout big cheers for them!
The game's over.
Team East Timor won!
Our young pIayers did
something unthinkabIe.
ln March 2004,
for the first time in the history of East Timor...
the youth soccer team
participated in an international match
the 30th Rivelino Cup in Hiroshima..
Against all odds,
they went on to win the championship
with 6 miraculous wins.